# **Dan Higgins**

Senior Frontend Engineer

07826173615

danhiggins23@outlook.com

danhiggins.info

linkedin.com/in/danhiggins23

#### **PROFILE**

Senior Frontend Engineer with 6+ years of professional experience, working in industries such as sports tech, e-commerce and banking, with clients such as Premier League, Myprotein, Santander and Ford. I pride myself in clean, maintainable code, with a focus on performance, accessibility and readability. I'm passionate about knowledge sharing, and constantly improving and adapting teams for success.

## **QUALIFICATIONS**

Teesside University BSc Digital Forensics, 1st Class Honours

Scrum.org Professional Scrum Master I

#### **COURSES**

## LinkedIn

React: Using TypeScript Developing for Web Performance

Open University Introduction to Cyber Security

## **SKILLS**

#### Front-end

React, Flow, Typescript, Redux & RTK, Emotion, JSS, Storybook, Stylequidist, MUI, Lerna

#### Testina

RTL, Jest, Enzyme, Playwright, Cypress, Selenium

## Others

Circle Ci, SonarQube, Eslint, Sentry, Grafana, Mixpanel, LaunchDarkly, Jenkins, Java, AEM

## **INTERESTS**



Football







### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Kitman Labs, 2022-Present - Senior Frontend Engineer

- Took initiative and leadership of data importer refactor and redesign - built with React, RTK and MUI, from concept, to arranging design and roll-out plan, which drastically improved key workflows for multiple high profile clients
- Scrum master within the squad, facilitating ceremonies, and constantly adapting and implementing changes to increase story point output, whilst becoming more accurate on estimations and reducing pain points
- Integral role in key initiatives including integrating playwright into our workflow, converting our architecture over to SPA, and implementing analytical tools such as Mixpanel and Google Tag Manager
- Ran full cost analysis on CircleCi workflows, to adjust resource usages which reduced failure rates and duration, as well as costs
- Reviewing CV's, Interviewing candidates, buddy-ing new starters and mentoring colleagues
- \* Technologies: React, RTK, Flow, RTL, Jest, Circle Cl

### THG, 2020-22 – Frontend Engineer

- Worked on a mixture of new features and BAU using a tech stack of primarily React, Redux, JSS & Java, within the checkout team
- Worked on and lead multiple large projects, all live, being used by thousands of customers daily
- Lead workshops to wider team showcasing features, new technology and possible codebase improvements
- \* Conducting interviews and mentored new starters in the team
- \* Technologies: React, JSS, Redux, Jest, Java, Jenkins

## Santander, 2020 – Software Engineer

- Integrated Cypress into Jenkins pipeline, to fully end-to-end test internal "rule engine" tool, built in
- Maintained and improved Java microservices
- Technologies: Angular, Java, Jenkins, Cypress

#### BT, 2018-19 – AEM/React Developer

- Building AEM components in Angular before transitioning into a React SPA implementation, building components, documenting using Styleguidist and ensuring high unit test coverage using Jest
- Technologies: React, Sass, AEM, Angular, Java, Jest

# Ford Motor Company, 2017 – Project Manager Internship

Co-managed an IT Infrastructure project to streamline and increase efficiency of servers, working with large amount of capital with remote teams